ILGWU Memorabilia Banners 5780/188 MB
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU Memorabilia Banners
1886-1977
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
5780/188 MB
47 cubic feet
47 linear ft.
Memorabilia.
The ILGWU Memorabilia Banners collection include banners from several ILGWU Locals and range in dates from the late 1800's to around 1950.
7128073
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, October 10, 2013
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 16, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000 in 1969.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5780: ILGWU records
Women's clothing industry -- Labor unions -- New York (State); Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- New York (State); International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union--Collectibles
7128073
- Ladies Garment Cutters Local 213 ILGWU of San Francisco California, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  - maroon; metal fringe, gold
- The United Cloak Suit, Infants and Children's Coat Operators and Sample Makers Union, Local 117 New York, ILGWU affiliated American Federation of Labor Organized March 1886 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - red/maroon; gold, metal trim
- International Ladies Garment Workers Union, Midwest Region, D.C.1, D.C.2, D.C.3 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  white (1 layer cotton/linen); blue letters; red, white and blue Union label; top sleeve for pole
- Waists, Silk Suits & Children's Dressmakers Union, Joint Board of Phila. Organized June 1906 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - red; yellow/gold text with black outline; white label with green eagle; fringe on 3 edges, text on 2 sides; sleeve on one edge for pole?
- S.F. Joint Board Locals 8, 101, 213, 214"; Union Label, "San Francisco, Calif., 1940-1950 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - red silk; fabric fringe; gold and black decoration, possibly hand stitched text
- Knitgoods, Workers Union, Local no. 191, International Ladies Garment Workers Union, Organized 1937 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - maroon with gold decoration; wool/felt; rayon acetate backing
- Office & Distribution Workers Local 214, San Francisco, Cal., Union Label (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - red; fabric fringe
- Local 215 International Ladies Garment Workers Union, AFL-CIO, NAPA SONOMA Counties, Est. 12-30-1977 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - red; yellow fabric fringe; large eagle, handshake
- Pacific Northwest District Council, Union Label, AFL CIO (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - blue with yellow fabric fringe - double sided
- Pacific Northwest District Council Locals 8, 101, 213, 214, 215"; Union Label, "San Francisco, Cal. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - red with fabric fringe
- Union Label"; Union Label, Symbol of Decency Fair Labor Standards and the American Way of Life (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - gold; silver trim on bottom (added at a later date?), silk screen; wood dowel with caps to thread through banner; synthetic; nylon over wood; maker's label; (same as #25 and #26)
- Dressmakers Union Local No. 101, International Ladies Garment Workers Union, San Francisco, Cal., Org. 1933 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - maroon; no lining
- International Ladies Garment Workers Union, Affiliated with the American Federation of Labor, Organized June 22, 1900 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - red; bright yellow edging, fringe and tassels; machine stitching, 2 cornucopias with torches
- Laundry, Dry Cleaning and Dye House Workers Union, Local No. 26, Org. 1901, San Francisco, Calif. (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - purple and gold; hand painted; silk?; metal fringe, gold and tassels; Union Label - has union bug 510 hand drawn
- International Ladies Garment Workers Union, Affiliated with the American Federation of Labor, Organized June 22, 1900 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - very similar to #13, except no tassels; red, with gold, pink, green, purple, red, and blue decoration; machine stitching, 2 cornucopias and 2 torches with grapes, leaves, fruit; ribbons, fringe, hanging loops
- Ladies Tailors, Custom Dressmakers, Alteration Workers, Union Local 38, ILGWU A.F. of L. Organized Oct. 1 1909 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - maroon; gold text; 2 hands holding torches tan, green, red, olive; stitched down cord; fringe along top and bottom; loops for hanging -satin
- Cloakmakers Union, Local No. 8, San Francisco, California, Organized 1901; Union Label (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - red; silk; gold fringe on bottom; gold letters with silver or green outline; stamped/hand painted; fringe on bottom; braided edges and top; 6 hanging loops
- International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, Legislative Department; Union Label "Made in U.S.A." (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - white; red, white and blue decoration
- Member of ILGWU, May 1941 Day; "Prompt 230" (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - blue and gold; wool/felt
- British Union Jack, 1900-1950 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - pieced sections red, white and blue faded to purple/brown; Nylon
- Flag of Canada (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - red stamped on white nylon; silk screened
- ILGWU Union Label (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - white; red and blue label on bottom half "Made in the USA"
- Union Label; Union Label, "Symbol of Decency Fair Labor Standards and the American Way of Life", 1930-1940 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - gold; silver trim on bottom (added at a later date?), silk screen; wood dowel with caps to thread through banner; synthetic; nylon over wood; maker's label; (same as #11 and #26)
- Banner rods: two rods from a banner, and two faded (blue/Silver) tassels (Box 25.1, Folder 1)
- Union Label"; Union Label, "Symbol of Decency Fair Labor Standards and the American Way of Life (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - gold; silver trim on bottom (added at a later date?), silk screen; wood dowel with caps to thread through banner; synthetic; nylon over wood; maker's label; (same as #11 and #25)
- "Int Ladies Garment Workers Union; NE, Western PA & Ohio Dept." (Box 29, Folder 1)
- Images digitized from the collection. (Box 30)